https://www.ethicalwares.com/privacy-and-cookie-policy

Orders
Track my order(s)
Track my order(s)
Sign inRegister
Email
PasswordForgot your password?
Orders
Track my order(s)
Track my order(s)
Sign inRegister
Email
PasswordForgot your password?
Register for a new account
Sign in
Remember me
Privacy & Cookie Policy of ethicalwares.comThis website collects some Personal Data from its Users.Owner and Data ControllerEthical WARESOwner contact emailvegans@ethicalwares.comWhat personal data we collect and why we collect itThis website uses Google Analytics and the Facebook Pixel, which enables the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behaviour.Google AnalyticsGoogle Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilises the Data collected to track and examine the use of this website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.Google may use the Data collected to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network.To opt out of Google Analytics tracking please see: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptoutFacebook PixelThe Facebook Pixel enables us to measure, optimise and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook. In particular it enables us to see how our users move between devices when accessing our web site and Facebook, to ensure that our Facebook advertising is seen by users most likely to be interested in it. This involves analysing which content a user has viewed and interacted with on our website.The Facebook Pixel also allows us to track how many customers purchased a product from our web store after clicking through from one of our Facebook adverts, to enable us to assess the effectiveness of our ads and help inform our future advertising strategy.
For further information on opting out of Facebook Pixel tracking, please see: https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferencesTypes of Data collectedAmong the types of Personal Data that this website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data and Data communicated while using the service.Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.Personal Data may be freely provided by the User (i.e. when completing a contact form), or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this website.Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this website to provide its services. In cases where this website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this website or by the owners of third-party services used by this website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.You can block Cookies at any time - full instructions on how to block Cookies in any web browser can be found by consulting this article: https://proprivacy.com/ruinmysearchhistory/how-to-...Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this website and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.Mode and place of processing the DataThe Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorised access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorised destruction of the Data.The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organisational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this website (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.Legal basis of processingThe Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:· Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;· provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;· processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;· processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;· processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.PlaceThe Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organisation governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.Retention timePersonal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.Therefore:· Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.· Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.The purposes of processingThe Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Content commenting, Interaction with external social networks and platforms and Interaction with live chat platforms.Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.The rights of UsersUsers may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.In particular, Users have the right to do the following:· Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.· Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.· Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.· Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.· Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.· Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.· Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller. Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User's consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.· Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.Details about the right to object to processingWhere Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.How to exercise these rightsAny requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.Additional information about Data collection and processingLegal actionThe User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this website or the related Services.The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.Additional information about User's Personal DataIn addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.System logs and maintenanceFor operation and maintenance purposes, this website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.Information not contained in this policyMore details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.How “Do Not Track” requests are handledThis website does not support “Do Not Track” requests.To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honour the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.Changes to this privacy policyThe Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within this website and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.Definitions and legal referencesPersonal Data (or Data)Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.Usage DataInformation collected automatically through this website (or third-party services employed in this website ), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilised by the Users who use this website , the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilised to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilised by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the website) and the details about the path followed within the website with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.UserThe individual using this website who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.Data SubjectThe natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.Data Controller (or Owner)The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this website.This websiteThe means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.ServiceThe service provided by this website as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this website.European Union (or EU)Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.CookiesSmall sets of data stored in the User's device. Legal informationThis privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).This privacy policy relates solely to this website, if not stated otherwise within this document.
Stay Connected
Exclusive discountsSubscribe to our news and get a 10% discount coupon!
your order or how become a stockist?
Website by InSynch
This site uses cookies to store information on your computer. See our cookie policy for further details on how to block cookies.
I am happy with this
